{
    "id": "09b5309468444fbda470236eb3889cd6",
    "title": "Infinitive With Or Without To",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I don’t let my children ……………………….. up late.",
            "description": "Let is followed by object + infinitive without to.",
            "answers": [
                "stay",
                "to stay",
                "staying"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "ba1bd6adcb1c49aba8f24468adf30e39"
        },
        {
            "question": "Try ……………………….. late.",
            "description": "We make negative infinitives by putting not before the infinitive.",
            "answers": [
                "to not be",
                "not to be",
                "not don't be"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "da7364572d5042029c9d9bb5957865b2"
        },
        {
            "question": "I made him …………………………. me my money back.",
            "description": "Make is followed by object + infinitive without to.",
            "answers": [
                "give",
                "to give",
                "giving"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "d44596e4d8b04284815e08948efdf190"
        },
        {
            "question": "She was heard …………………………. that she was quitting.",
            "description": "The infinitive is used with to after passive forms of hear.",
            "answers": [
                "say",
                "to say",
                "saying"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "e98b3b8a42ba479e9508c5e4c6fd914a"
        },
        {
            "question": "I would like to lie down and ………………………….. to sleep.",
            "description": "When we connect two infinitive structures with ‘and’, the second one is usually without to.",
            "answers": [
                "to go",
                "go",
                "going"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "1ba758f56a314e64b626b89c519c7092"
        },
        {
            "question": "Rather than ………………………… anymore, I decided to go home.",
            "description": "Rather than is followed by an infinitive without to.",
            "answers": [
                "wait",
                "to wait",
                "waiting"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "c49d7b7b4ef848cfa6d96d0de99080c0"
        },
        {
            "question": "I have to feed the dogs as well as ……………………………. the plants.",
            "description": "When we connect two infinitive structures with as well as, the second one is usually without to.",
            "answers": [
                "water",
                "watering",
                "to water"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "5a1d945ea4404fa18a53fa9625acf582"
        },
        {
            "question": "She needn’t ............................................... any longer.",
            "description": "When need is used as a modal auxiliary verb, it is followed by an infinitive without to.",
            "answers": [
                "wait",
                "to wait",
                "waiting"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "3b58cd48be0d4015868304f35ac0b5fc"
        },
        {
            "question": "You look tired. Why not ………………………… some rest?",
            "description": "We can introduce suggestions with why not + infinitive without to.",
            "answers": [
                "to get",
                "getting",
                "get"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "f7e29d458d964b01a401652bd4632f83"
        },
        {
            "question": "Do you want to leave now or …………………………… until they arrive?",
            "description": "When we connect two infinitive structures with or, the second one is usually without to.",
            "answers": [
                "wait",
                "to wait",
                "waiting"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "9911c1651c7644819393464fceee1e8b"
        },
        {
            "question": "I am ready to do anything but ……………………….",
            "description": "When we connect two infinitive structures with but, the second one is usually without to.",
            "answers": [
                "to cook",
                "cooking",
                "cook"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "7f744c3c8d2e42edba67edb73f42d43b"
        },
        {
            "question": "Do you feel the earth …………………………….?",
            "description": "After feel + object, the infinitive is used without to.",
            "answers": [
                "move",
                "to move",
                "moving"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "df551922459a4c04a028d903154e5fd0"
        }
    ]
}